<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Tyler Smith</title>
    <link>/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Tyler Smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Blood Donations: Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/predicting-blood-donations-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predicting-blood-donations-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Purpose This post shows some basic modeling methods in R. Specifically, I model blood donation data with a linear and logit model. These models are well established an easy to inerpret. In a future post I’ll explore some more flexible models that might improve prediction.
Linear regression with lm A linear model is the simplest and best understood method for modeling data, as well as a building block for more sophisticated methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on The Elements of Statistical Learning</title>
      <link>/post/notes-on-the-elements-of-statistical-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/notes-on-the-elements-of-statistical-learning/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The Bias-Variance Tradeoff Note: Statistics vs Econometrics  Tree-based Methods   Purpose The Elements of Statistical Learning by Hastie et. al. is the best resource I’ve found for understanding modern statistical and machine learning techniques. These techniques aim to answer problems of the following kind: what’s the best approximation to the conditional expectation function \(f(x) = E[Y|X]\)? Or more generally, what is our best guess for \(Y\) given what we know about \(X\)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Blood Donations: Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/predicting-blood-donations-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predicting-blood-donations-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Purpose This post shows some basic R usage, data cleaning and exploration, and visualization methods. In Part 2, I explore some quantitative methods.
Obtaining data in R R has a useful function called download.file, which I show here for future reference. Using the option method = curl, and maybe the extra option to pass additional arguments, I can download data from the DrivenData website.
training_data_url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/drivendata/data/2/public/ 9db113a1-cdbe-4b1c-98c2-11590f124dd8.csv&amp;quot; train_file &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>